all right I got I got a question that I
think I've answered before I'm going to
go ahead and answer again though Rob
don't want to distract but want to talk
to you about how you organize your day
or week uh my how passionate you are
love to learn more okay so the first
things first I am not a pro at this I'm
just old okay I'm just old and I've
learned a lot of lessons the hard way
and and anybody that's been on my
channel for a decent amount of time
knows how much I
fail um at organizing my time and stuff
but I do want to talk about
um the ways that I feel like I have
succeeded in the past and in the you
know presently and lessons I've learned
the hard way and some of them I was kind
of right on some things I was wrong on
so the first thing I was right on is a
schedule you you really do need a
schedule my wife would argue that you
don't need one she and I are that's
another thing learning about how your
how your brain works and how you work um
I think there's pretty good science at
this point that routine and schedule is
by far uh the most effective way to
achieve what you want want and you know
and i' I've been active in Triathlon
Durant sports for a long time and one of
the the the the main things you know any
kind of training reement is that you've
got to stick to a routine so um I
recently wrote a lot about this in my
zcast and after I attempted hi I'm
making a video but I
talk my wife's going to walk the dog she
wanted to invite
me yeah she always comes in like right
when I'm making a video it's like I
literally was out there trying to talk
to her for the last 10 minutes and she's
like I can't talk so that's another
thing making time for the things that
are important right don't
don't she's making coffee now and I was
just making Cofe I was like hey we
should have copy and then now she's off
the
phone maybe that I'm just going to leave
that in the
video copy is included in the thing so
routine routine and schedule that's
going to help um if you're if you're an
ath if you're an athlete of any kind at
no edits I know if you're an athlete of
any kind then you absolutely know that
you're going to you just have to do it
just start your fitness journey yeah
routine routine is the way to go and
routine is whe whether the routine is
going to help you with Fitness routine
is going to help you achieve your goals
period And since I stopped thinking that
I could live on I I thought that by you
know employing some form of regimented
routine while on the road on my bike
trying to work while also on the road
that I could win I was wrong I was wrong
you can't there's just too much
distraction and that was too much
blowing away the routine my health went
down my finances went down my safety
went down I caught covid um and you know
I had a lot of adventurous fun and
everything but but and my my I forgot a
lot of things I wasn't able to do other
things that I wanted to do and when I
came home and I settled down I got back
to my routine again which is some of you
will notice I got my schedule on the
board here and I started most
importantly I started doing yoga so I I
really really strongly believe that you
need to have something that causes your
heart rate to rise and to get that
dopamine and the dpin going for at least
an hour half an hour to an hour a day
every day and it should be at a regular
time I I cannot swear I cannot tell you
more how that is a thing there's a
saying in Yoga Yoga Yoga Yoga and all is
coming and I really believe it um I
particularly like yoga because I have a
hard time calming my mind down and
staying heal and you know keeping muscle
mass at my age and everything and yoga
checks all those boxes so that's a part
of it right discipline R motivation it
is and I mean everybody from you know Mr
Navy SEAL what's his name you know
they're all going to agree on that right
so uh discipline is is important for
motivation now to be fair you should you
should also kind of balance that with uh
you know kindness you need to be kind to
yourself and to your family and those
around you I have been so when I was a
triathlete I was so disciplined and so
Reg mented that if something got in the
way of my training I was I was a grumpy
[__] and I'm not proud of that I I
there were it's not a lot of times I was
overtrained right I had done too much
training because I had to stick with the
schedule you stay with discipline you
know and I got to and I didn't I wasn't
listening to my body and it wasn't until
uh I started doing yoga as a as a
replacement for religion frankly and
after I got left you know left the
Mormon Church the Mormons taught me a
lot about being a regimented person I
was a missionary I was actually a
missionary instructor for two years uh I
lived with the missionaries in the
residence hall so I I have a lot of um
background
in hey thank you for that I have a lot
of background in reg Manu Pro
1,410 is now following um a lot you know
it's funny because I I do find a lot of
people in the military particularly in
it do really well and I think it's one
of the same this for the same reasons I
think a lot of them will learn
discipline um and you know the military
is a great place to learn Tech honestly
depending if you can get out a live
right um and we talk about the Mormon
thing later I was 42 it was a long it
was a long deal um messages are a tad
loud all right I'll turn them down there
you
go I don't know how how low that is but
it's lower um so so that's it the
regimen discipline routine um but when
you add these things so anybody's been
watching me for any amount of time we
see me make a really filled schedule
Bam's probably laughing right now but
they'll see me make a really filled
schedule like down to I'm going to have
a map at this time I'm going to drink
coffee at this time whatever literally
I'm going to take a poop right
here and then and then I'll like do it
for a week and I'll be like oh my God
there's no way I can do this this is
driving me crazy I feel like I'm a
prisoner to my own routine and then I'm
like okay this whole schedule is going
out and and anybody who knows me knows
that that on that way my wife would tell
she'd be laughing um you know my wife
would be like oh yeah so like I'm all or
nothing I'm like black or white I'm I'm
very I'm very dichotomous someone say I
might even be manic depressive at some
point actually I think I might actually
be um bottom line that a certain amount
of balance in your routine and it's some
of the reason I love yoga because
especially aanga aanga is like you're
going to do this routine on your own
every day and you're going to variated
it you know as you will St so even
asanga I have decided no I don't want to
do that that's not good for my body
particularly my neck so I'm going to do
this other thing and I'm going to put it
in there because I guard said I could
and so the takeaway is schedule
routine uh and and creating habits and
and sweating getting dopamine in your
system getting the oxygen in your system
all of those things will help the rest
to happen and and that includes
scheduled learning times you know every
Friday afternoon is my scheduled you
know Learning Time based on my company
my company gives us that time for free
to work to learn on whatever we want and
um yeah but I'm zero 100% a lot of times
and I don't you know so um you know
making times for relationships with
others um but I can't overemphasize how
important your physical health is as I
age I've noticed that um how much I took
for
granted uh my physical health and how
much it impacted my
brain um I at my age I regular because I
don't producing as much growth hormone
and testosterone All That Jazz I'm not
on any kind of tea therapy or anything I
um I regularly take a 20 30 minute nap
particularly in the afternoon sometimes
I'll take two of them and I'll I'll take
a nap and I'll wake up and then I do a
coffee nap you guys know about this I'll
either have copy right after that uh is
it 23 don't it's if it's 304 if it's
over 30 minutes then you get groggy if
for me if it's under 20 minutes it's not
enough and everybody's different you all
have that amount of sleep that you can
do before you enter start in a rem State
you wake up in a rem State you're in a
mess so naps naps is a thing that I do
and I I've been doing this my whole life
and whether I wanted to or not when I
was a kid I used to fall asleep on my my
head on the you know drooling all over
the desk in my biology class I'd wake up
all refreshed and ready for I don't know
uh driver's ed you know so I think I
think Tak learning to manage your your
take you know sleep and stuff is
important do I have do I have speciic no
I don't if I'm if I'm feeling really
sleepy I will just lay down and I'll
take like a 20-minute nap and I'll
either wake up and get coffee or
sometimes I'll have coffee before I take
a nap they do as a copy nap
thing sometimes I take a nap and I end
up I end up crossing over into REM State
and I sleep for three hours I'm a remote
employee so as long as I make up the
time and I didn't miss a meeting that's
fine and not everybody has that
flexibility it's one of the reasons that
working from home to me is worth at
least 30 to 50 Grand and I I will never
go back to work hell no I've been
working remote since
1994 five
six
seven I'm trying to remember when the
bottom line is is um I mean some people
can't do that some people can you know I
also have learned this is another this
is a big thing in terms of efficiency
and performance I've learned when to do
things that are important so like you
saw my wife come in
right I get a lot of Highly focused work
done either in the late night times or
in the early morning when nobody's here
um I get and I've just learned I I know
when those times are that I'm not going
to be distracted right um and another
thing too that hasn't doesn't really do
well for my proficiency but it certainly
does for my motivation and that's doing
the streaming and I think I'm probably
going to end on this um Power naaps yeah
it's got to be slow um I I actually I my
personality type deres a lot of energy
from interaction with others
um you know I it's just my personality
type I my wife is she'll say it even
more than I will she's like you thrive
off of interaction with others it's like
your it's like your power source if you
don't have interaction you you know I
can get focused I can get focused in
code but having an
audience I'm very sad to say motivates
me it motivates me it keeps me going um
it it fills me full of whatever it is it
keeps me motivated um not everybody's
like that so I maybe the take away from
that is to know what it is that um that
helps you so so to give you a specific
example there's another great twitch
streamer B7 uh maybe if somebody wants
to shout out B7 B7 two years ago uh I
think it was started streaming um and
and I he if I remember how he said it
right he's like you know Rob inter you
know kind of encouraged him to do it and
I told him I said look I said we
actually need more beginners streaming
who are just learning
things um he is awesome and he's grown
as a streamer I mean he's got all kinds
of things he's got a community in there
not everybody's a streamer but those of
you who are learning who get your power
off of that who get that that that you
know that that Vibe really helps you
he's amazing and you know but he early
on he would say you know I was listening
to Robin and he told me I should stream
even if I'm a beginner I was like no I
don't want to I'm like no we need more
beginners we need beginners to stream
because those are the people that can
that are relatable those are the people
the reason I'm not afraid of making
really crazy new mistakes even though
I'm a senior is because that's what
people want to see they want to see how
you're you're a real person um I just
watched a whole documentary about the
downfall of um shock jock what's his
name uh and how he's been replaced by
Joe Rogan
and as the as the
Everyman uh you know uh podcaster um Joe
Rogan replaced U what's the other what's
the other guy's name see my brain is not
working where's my copy but the point is
is that people want they want to
relatable people they they want they
want to watch people who are okay
streaming takes energy okay and if how
turn yeah so but the point is is he was
relatable and he makes mistakes and he's
he's vulnerable and all that stuff right
and um you know when I first started
streaming I was just doing you know the
hoodie thing and I was worried about now
I'm like you know fixing my zits and
like talking about my teeth on stream
I've come full circle um stream is not
for everybody as kulus will tell you um
there are some people to take energy of
it there's some people who it saps their
energy so much they can't do it takes
way too much energy for them to do it um
I did stop streaming for a while because
it does take energy and I do get
distracted um in a way that I enjoy and
that's why I get
distracted uh Mark here comes Mark here
comes
Mark here comes Mark to keep it
real so per me routine schedule good
health relationships and uh finding
those times when it's quiet and finding
out what motivates you uh taking breaks
and taking naps pretty basic stuff I I
don't think you need like a a degree in
you know
performance I will say this I I do time
box a little bit but I don't time box I
got rid of the Pomo thing because it was
just stressing me out I time box but
it's a more of a it's more of a a
regular thing oh God uh use them as your
daily thing as you were just getting rid
of of that
nice uh how do I decide when to do what
and for how long honest to God that
depends on my brain
I bike yeah I haven't biked in two
weeks I haven't biked in two weeks no
I've just been getting but I'm getting
way
healthier yeah my muscle mass is like
way higher yeah so I am not regretting
it at
all yeah Mark is this is Mark Mark's
here for the biking and I don't do
anymore I do it I just don't do it as
much it's in the it's in the calendar I
talked about it on November 3rd I'm
going to go back to biking more
regularly I need right now I need to to
move I'm moving a thing so how do I
decide when to do what I do it I do
whatever I feel like doing so that I can
just do it and sometimes like like
there's been several times when I've had
a really big chronic attack of
inflammation really inflamed really not
chronic acute attack and I can't think
my brain doesn't work and taking na
ain't going to fix it when those kind of
times happen I'll usually default over
to you know doing whatever it I need to
to kind of restore my energy and my
health and stuff sometimes I'll watch a
movie or something in the middle of the
day uh just to kind of get my brain back
going on and then but inevitably my
personality type inevitably there will
be a time when I can really really grind
hard and and come back um in Mexican
restaurants oh that was fun that was fun
we need do more of that
Mark uh we do need AR mix meet up all
you guys are in North Carolina too
you're on YouTube by the way say hi to
YouTube all right so um honestly
everybody's different don't let any the
biggest thing is don't let anybody tell
you what to do you're the only one who
knows you you're the only one that knows
your body you're the only one that knows
what motivates you uh just kind of think
about what those things are and uh maybe
consider something like yoga I mean yoga
or meditation or reflection th those are
opportunities Journal writing those are
all opportunities for you to discover
the things about yourself uh and put it
down on paper that nobody can tell you
and the more in tune you know know
thyself the more in tune you are with
who you are and if there's one thing
that age does give you it's that it
gives you knowledge about what you can
do what you can't do what you can eat
what you can't eat what you know what
motivates you who you need to be around
all of those things and the wiser you
can get the younger the better because
then you can make those decis decisions
earlier in life and and you can act on
them and be aware of it and and just
kind of accept who you are and that
those are very very you know touchy
peely kind of deep thought Deep Thoughts
with Jack
Handy kind of ideas but it's true it's
true you you've got to figure out who
you are and the only way you can do that
is you know be still and and to to look
inside and and to go for a walk or to
you know listen to that really close
friend or or family member who gives it
to you straight um and once you figure
out who you are then the the
efficiencies will come the things like
they you just naturally the more you the
more I feel in tune with myself and
right now I feel really in tune with
myself because I've honest to God
because I've been doing yoga every day
yoga has given me an opportunity yoga is
designed to do this Yoga Yoga is one of
the unique activities that is
specifically designed to unlock
you it unlocks you it unlocks you
physically it unlocks you mentally um it
it it unblocks things emotions that
you've had that are holding you back it
it gives you new ideas after I've done
yoga and I'm in the I'm in the shower or
the restroom I have I'm flooded with
ideas for things that that that I you
know because I always say when you're
not thinking about it directly right
it's that secondary thing these ideas
come to me that are that you know when I
was Mormon I would have said that I was
getting prompted by the Holy Ghost for
things I don't believe that's true I
think they cist calling it by a
different name but but I I get direct
inspiration um when after a yoga session
or or or after a biking session or while
I'm biking um I I do believe there's
something related to the the oxygen and
the the dopamine and all of that that's
that's going to that's going to unlock
ideas uh and those ideas some of those
are going to make you more efficient
steuart SMY yes did I say Jack Handy
it's a different person s SM yeah got it
wrong thank you for that so anyway I
mean that's a much longer video than I
wanted to make um and I'm going to I'm
going to go ahead and and push stop on
that video right now